<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Balaji Srinivasan</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.balaaagi.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Trip to Kumbakonam July 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This trip was planned initially to transfer some goods but later dropped off. We again planned for the trip over the first weekend of July 2014.
Our initial plan was to see all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Navagraha_temples&quot;&gt;Navagraha Temples&lt;/a&gt; kinda of little holy trip:P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travellers&lt;/strong&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;www.balaaagi.me&quot;&gt;Myself&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/komahanpaulraj&quot;&gt;Ko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dinesh.rajee.7&quot;&gt;Dinesh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=1781440509&quot;&gt;Manoj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mode&lt;/strong&gt;-Road by Maruti Swift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the initial planning I researched on the routes for the temples from Kumbakonam. The first search result provided some good map route which seems to cover the whole &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kumbakonam&quot;&gt;Kumbakonam district&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;http://kumbakonamtemples.in/navagraha-temple-route-maps.html&quot;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; was what we had as base for our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip Day 1- July 5, 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I packed myself for the trip took my Mac also along with since had few assignments that need to be completed thought would finish over the travel in car. We started around 6:30 AM as usual we delayed by half an hour leading us to drop in total plan. Our first stop was near &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madras_Export_Processing_Zone&quot;&gt;MEPZ&lt;/a&gt; for breakfast. We had our breakfast in GK hotel which is famous in GST road.
After the breakfast it time to burn the tyres. Dinesh was driving at consistent speed. We had a confusion on whether to reach Kumbakonam via Koliyanur Road or via Pondy–&amp;gt; Chidambaram…
Later we confirmed that we will proceed with Pondy Route. But near Tindivanam we missed a left which made us to roam for another 1 hr. 
Later we took Mailam road and reached Kallanai.
In the meantime our mobile charges went down and the charger connected with the car does not charge the mobile phone.
So we were lost. Later we tethered the internet from another mobile used by Mac to find the map route and proceeded. It was around 1:30 by the time when we reached Kumbakonam.
We refreshed ourselves at Ko’s brother &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/palesh.paulraj&quot;&gt;Palesh&lt;/a&gt; anna’s residence and proceeded with our plan. But now our plan changed due to timings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we headed towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brihadeeswarar_Temple&quot;&gt;Tanjore Big Temple&lt;/a&gt; which is around 40kms from Kumbakonam. We reached there before the sunset and we were able to view the temple towers in sunlight. Later we headed towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kailasanthar_Temple,Thingalur&quot;&gt;Thingalur Moon Temple&lt;/a&gt; which was 14 km in North from the Big temple. By the time we reached there it was almost 6-7. Later we moved towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swaminathaswamy_Temple,_Swamimalai&quot;&gt;Swamimalai&lt;/a&gt; . It started to rain heavily when we came out after offering our prayers. We halted for a while and started and headed towards Kumbakonam. 
It was raining heavily in Kumbakonam. Also the streets of Kumbakonam were flooded. Whatever routes we took to reach the residence for sure car would start to float. Water level were so high. We were roaming for all routes like this for an hour. After which we somehow found a street and drove fast to our street. In the street there was no flood it was little elevated compared to other streets. We escaped:P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we reached home all started to sleep since we have to start early next day. But I have not completed my code assignments hence was awake until aroun 1:00 AM and slept afterwards. It was raining till that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip Day 2- July 6 ,2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We still have 8 more temples to see due to the change in plan and we have almost half a day since we have to head towards Chennai by atleast 3:00 PM. So we started early around 6:00 AM.
We headed towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thirunageswaram&quot;&gt;Rahu Temple&lt;/a&gt;. We finished there and visited the nearby &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uppiliappan_Temple&quot;&gt;Uppulipian Temple&lt;/a&gt;.The temple was closed until 9:00 AM due to some rituals. Hence we came out and had our breakfast to check whether as said by facts “all food outside the temple will not have salt!!”
Later when the temple is opened for darshan we prayed and started from there to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apatsahayesvarar_Temple,_Alangudi&quot;&gt;Jupiter Temple&lt;/a&gt;. From there we visited the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suryanar_Kovil&quot;&gt;Sun Temple&lt;/a&gt; and later the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agniswarar_Temple,_Kanjanur&quot;&gt;Venus Temple&lt;/a&gt;.
It was almost lunch time. From there we headed towards &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaitheeswaran_Koil&quot;&gt;Vaiteeswaran Temple&lt;/a&gt;. On our way we had tugs with a local for hitting our car. It took us some time.
By the time we reached the temple, they were about to close the premises for lunch time.We quickly prayed and came out before they close the temple.
The place was famous for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naadi&quot;&gt;Nadi Astrology&lt;/a&gt; and few of them were seeing it after we had our lunch. It was around 2 when we started back to Kumbakonam and within few minutes we started back to Chennai.
This time we came via Koliyanur route which was pretty simple and clear. Throughout our journey towards Chennai we were being accompanied by heavy rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atlast it was very holy trip but missed three temples according to our plan….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another weekend spent seeking the blessing of lords:)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 19:17:04 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/trip-to-kumbakonam-july-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/trip-to-kumbakonam-july-2014</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>March 2014 Devlogs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The month started with plan to learn &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;. With little knowledgable in javascript was very much reluctant or does not have much confident in starting or diving into node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So initially thought of downloading some ebooks and just follow what they have said.
But later thought let us do it with a simple project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my long idea of saving the links I visited to a place for future reference is the project I choosed. But where to start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help came in hand with this &lt;a href=&quot;http://cwbuecheler.com/web/tutorials/2013/node-express-mongo/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorial has a simple app to store user id and email id in mongo db and retrieve and show to users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of using that I made my idea live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1 was installation which I had done a year back with eagerness to learn node. So basic node with npm is already installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2 was to install &lt;a href=&quot;http://expressjs.com/&quot;&gt;express&lt;/a&gt;. I learnt that it is web application framework for single and multi page web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -g express&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3 Create Basic Express application by simple command.
&lt;code&gt;express --sessions mylinks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 4 Adding the dependencies.
       Whatever I am gonna use it in my application all the related dependencies must be configured here(I have written it under my way of understanding)
Done in the file that is being created as part of express routine.
&lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;
This was my initial config in package.json&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;MyLinks&quot;,
  &quot;version&quot;: &quot;0.0.1&quot;,
  &quot;private&quot;: true,
  &quot;scripts&quot;: {
    &quot;start&quot;: &quot;node app.js&quot;
  },
  &quot;dependencies&quot;: {
    &quot;express&quot;: &quot;3.4.8&quot;,
    &quot;jade&quot;: &quot;*&quot;,
    &quot;mongodb&quot;:&quot;*&quot;,
    &quot;monk&quot;:&quot;*&quot;
  }
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LearnBoost/monk&quot;&gt;monk&lt;/a&gt; is used for accessing MongoDB from Node.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With initial learning about Mongo DB queries using &lt;a href=&quot;https://education.mongodb.com&quot;&gt;MongoDB University&lt;/a&gt; was easily able to insert and retrieve data from MongoDB collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had the difficulty in understanding the how Node.js application works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then got a grap of it. Let me put in my works of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the neccesary dependencise will be included using &lt;code&gt;require&lt;/code&gt;.
An object of &lt;code&gt;express&lt;/code&gt; is mainly used for routing.
Based on the url with which the object being used the corresponding routes are used and provide the response.
To access the database db objects which are created using monk are passed to the routes function. 
From the routes function corresponding jade which is the layouts being rendered to the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With intial Setup and code written I was able to select the data from the db and display. But had issues while displaying with JADE. The indentations made it worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the next feature of adding links to the db.
Created a simple form using JADE and on submit called a url which inturn has the neccesary the logic to store in db by getting values from the request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then added the feature for having tags to the links.
We can store array of mutiple values to a column(field) in MongoDB since it is similar to JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stored the tags in the way. Retrieving and displaying again got some trouble with JADE. Used for loop to fetch all the links and for each link had a for loop for all the tags within it. Again indentation problem arised but fixed with option in Sublime to convert spaces to indentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now adding the tags had a problem. How the user will add the tags. We cannot be sure of how many tags can a link be associated with. Hence planned to get user input with comma separated. And fetched the field value and split it using commas and store in array and passed to addlink route.
&lt;code&gt;tags=req.body.tags.split(&quot;,&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later want to try another driver used for accessing MongoDB from Node.js. It was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/mongoskin&quot;&gt;mongoskin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modified the package.json&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
{
  &quot;name&quot;: &quot;MyLinks&quot;,
  &quot;version&quot;: &quot;0.0.1&quot;,
  &quot;private&quot;: true,
  &quot;scripts&quot;: {
    &quot;start&quot;: &quot;node app.js&quot;
  },
  &quot;dependencies&quot;: {
    &quot;express&quot;: &quot;3.4.8&quot;,
    &quot;jade&quot;: &quot;*&quot;,
    &quot;mongodb&quot;:&quot;*&quot;,
    &quot;mongoskin&quot;:&quot;*&quot;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The db object creation part differs from that of monk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the way in which collections are accessed are also differnt. Hence modified the changes.
Added links between the pages.
My first web application with Node.js,MongoDB,Express and Jade is done.
Find the code in below path
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/balaaagi/MyLinks&quot;&gt;https://github.com/balaaagi/MyLinks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few more features to be added in coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was too slow to complete this learning itself. Hope I pick the pace soon…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 23:57:55 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/march-2014-devlogs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/march-2014-devlogs</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My look Ahead for 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;updated-on-august-3-2014&quot;&gt;UPDATED ON AUGUST 3, 2014&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes as the title says the post is about my plan(rough one) for 2014. Usually at the start of the year I plan and think to do lot of things but this year I am going to be very serious is making it up. Below are the list of things that I have planned to do in this year without failing. I will be striking out the things once I have completed it. This post will be regularly updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Spend More time with family&lt;br /&gt;
*Do only things that make me feel happy in job&lt;br /&gt;
*Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/1128111&quot;&gt;30 Books&lt;/a&gt; for the year.&lt;br /&gt;
*~~Go the Bachelor’s dream place in India -&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=goa&amp;amp;espv=210&amp;amp;es_sm=119&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=jqkAU5zVE8amrAfFoIGwBw&amp;amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAg&amp;amp;biw=1278&amp;amp;bih=629#q=goa&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;imgdii=_&quot;&gt;Goa&lt;/a&gt;~~&lt;br /&gt;
*Eat Breakfast, lunch &amp;amp; dinner on time without fail&lt;br /&gt;
*Go for Mid Sea Diving @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=mid+sea+diving+kovalam&amp;amp;espv=210&amp;amp;es_sm=119&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=hKoAU4mlIMWHrQeRtoDQCg&amp;amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAg&amp;amp;biw=1278&amp;amp;bih=629&quot;&gt;Kovalam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
*Go for minimum 3 Treks this year&lt;br /&gt;
*Learn to Swim&lt;br /&gt;
*Learn to drive 4 Wheeler&lt;br /&gt;
*Partipate in local Marathon and try completing 10K mark&lt;br /&gt;
*Try completing atleast one online course per two months in any of MOOCS platform(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udacity.com/&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org&quot;&gt;Courseera&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/&quot;&gt;edX&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://academicearth.org/&quot;&gt;Academic Earth&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
*Contribute to a Open Source Project effectively&lt;br /&gt;
*Participate in lot of Hackathons and build more&lt;br /&gt;
*Try to give a tech talk in some meetup&lt;br /&gt;
*Become a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omscs.gatech.edu/&quot;&gt;GT OMSCS&lt;/a&gt; Student&lt;br /&gt;
*Apply to Hacker School and try getting admitted
&lt;br /&gt;
The above are the list which  I have prepared when I start the year. Anything or any additional things I want to include in the list I will add after the below line. Keeping my finger crossed to achieve 100% in the above list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 17:19:55 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/my-look-ahead-for-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/my-look-ahead-for-2014</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You aren't gonna need it approach for legacy applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I learnt about one more agile terminology. Eventhough my project is following &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall_model&quot;&gt;Classic SDLC&lt;/a&gt; I am expediting agile methodolgies like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development&quot;&gt;TDD&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban_%28development%29&quot;&gt;Kanban&lt;/a&gt; and few more still expediting. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why am I doing this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Just to make my job interesting by myself and set myself on par with real industry&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I just learnt one another term which is used in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extreme_programming&quot;&gt;XP&lt;/a&gt;. The term is  &lt;strong&gt;YAGNI&lt;/strong&gt;. I got know such a term exist from a quora &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Computer-Programming/Do-you-respect-the-YAGNI-principle-when-coding/answer/Kiran-Gangadharan?share=1&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I dunno the term alone but once i read about it I came to know this is very much applying in my daily job of writing code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YAGNI stands for &lt;strong&gt;You aren’t gonna need it!!&lt;/strong&gt;. I learnt more about it from the Quora &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quora.com/Computer-Programming/Do-you-respect-the-YAGNI-principle-when-coding/answer/Kiran-Gangadharan?share=1&quot;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_aren%27t_gonna_need_it&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how this applies to my daily job?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I develop for a legacy applications which has been live in production for more than seven years. In order to make my job interesting and leverage my Software development skills I try different ways/methodologies to do development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when developing in AGILE we focus on iterations to make users see the product with minimal working functionalities and improve them over the iterations. In that case we will be focussing only on the requirements and we won’t be developing additional features or add additional codes which may be useful in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But currently I am unable to do this with my development work since legacy applications run across various countries with same flow. So now when I change a part of code or add a new piece of code to existing part I may have to consider not following the YAGNI principle. Since legacy applications developments usually happens(as far as I know) by tranforming the existing flow of logic from one technology(Initial old technology) to latest new technology. Few of them happens by writing from scratch which just provides the functionalities, whereas most of them follows transforming the logic into different programming language. As result of this adding new features is having great impact on exiting live code.
For example lets consider a new feature of developing a interface from legacy system to a financial system. In this case when I develop the new interface feature I have consider writing code for all the scenarios in which the existing legacy system works(eg.countrywise).Even though the interface might/won’t be available in future. 
So writing such codes for legacy applications makes the development process more complex by unit testing a piece of code that won’t be used when it goes live as part of this release.This has following impacts directly
*Delivery time may get delayed. &lt;br /&gt;
*Users may not be able to see the feature on time.&lt;br /&gt;
*Developer’s focus on current deliverables shift to a more generalized solution which may not be thought during the analysis/design phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From management perspective they want the feature to be more generic such that write once deploy anywhere. But for applications where the logic has been merely transformed from legacy code this may not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am facing the above issue very much in my development nowadays…..There are two solutions for my problems
*Either follow AGILE process completely where our focus completely on current release alone so developer need not think about future implementations
*Rewrite the code completely with more object oriented language such the implementations are so easy with minor tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/you-arent-gonna-need-it-approach-for-legacy-applications</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/you-arent-gonna-need-it-approach-for-legacy-applications</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacker School may be my next target</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With so much frustration in office work , not doing things which I like and wanna do always and not able to give my 100% in work and I was completely stressed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The learnings I got in corporate were mostly of mangement things which I usually feel sick about!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I have been trying to participate in various tech forums, meetups and Hackathons to learn the intersting parts of technology which I always dreamt about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually I was very much sad that I did not have any internet connection in my home during my college days to get such exposure. It was only during my final year project internet was made available after which I was in responsibility to search job for the survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But moving into corporate washed away all my dreams of becoming techy guy as I wanted to .Many will ask “What effort did I put to make myself as such?”. Yeah initial one and half years in corporate passed away trying to prove that I can do development works.Where in the hell will I get time to concentrate. Almost spent more than 15 hrs in office to prove them that I can do coding!!Basically I learnt to do coding only!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that started participating in tech forums,meetups.FB group &lt;a href=&quot;http://chennaigeeks.in/home&quot;&gt;Chennai Geeks&lt;/a&gt; was my favourite through which I gained, learnt manythings.Then participating in Govt Data Hackathon gave me some more confidence. After that started taking online courses at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udacity.com/&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then from one of the google searches I came to about bootcamp programs which is very famous in US. I missed to hear or may be I was blind over these words during my college days.If I had heard I might have atleast given a try. After reading online blogs about bootcamp only this word is stuck with me for the past two days.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackerschool.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very much attracted towards the tagline 
&amp;gt;Hacker School is a writers’ retreat for programmers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principles of Hacker School are gr8 really gr8 like which I dreamt of
*Self Directed&lt;br /&gt;
*Accessible&lt;br /&gt;
*Stimulating&lt;br /&gt;
*Exceptional&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically it’s free for all but getting in is difficult.Also only we have to take care of our expenses for our stay there in NY city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past two days I have been just going through their website many times and thought of applying for their 2014 batch. But something was stoppping me. May be I should just build few more things and learn quite bit more before I apply since I am used to very bad corporate IT culture which really won’t make fit to get in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 my next target might be this for applying and getting selected for one of their batch.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 19:54:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/hacker-school-may-be-my-next-target</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/hacker-school-may-be-my-next-target</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I am unable to Showcase my Coding publicly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was designing my long pending personal website I have added &lt;a href=&quot;www.github.com&quot;&gt;GithHub&lt;/a&gt; profile link. But what could I find in Github were just two repositories.
*Initial GitHub Practicing repository
*Govt Data Hackathon repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have done few personal projects and developed few applications I am unable showcase it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reason for it most of the applications I did were done in my company as part of the internal contest.The ideas that I developed or prototyped might not be applicable for public or available for social coding where other can have a sneak peak on it and provide their valuable feedback for me to improve myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to this I hosted these projects in &lt;a href=&quot;www.bitbucket.com&quot;&gt;BitBucket&lt;/a&gt; in private repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully once I have started developing apps or my personal projects I will completely host in GitHub itself for my benefits atleast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:32:41 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/why-i-am-unable-to-showcase-my-coding-publicly</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/why-i-am-unable-to-showcase-my-coding-publicly</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple HTTPServer in MacOSX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was trying to setup a local &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_server&quot;&gt;webserver&lt;/a&gt;.
I need it because, I was learning &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Protovis#Context&quot;&gt;D3&lt;/a&gt; a javascript library after getting to know about it from Geeks Night session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I was downloading MAMP, but due to awesome internet connectivity I almost lost my patience since it was taking more than 40 minutes to download. On searching in internet for other options I found that there is a charm in Mac OS X due to preinstalled Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are trying with HTML,CSS and javascript this option will be very usefull.
Try the below in Terminal Window
&lt;code&gt;python -m SimpleHTTPServer &amp;lt;port-number&amp;gt; &amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will start a local HTTP server in your Mac.
Access it via browser in below url
&lt;code&gt;http://localhost:&amp;lt;port-number&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to shutdown the server just close the Terminal window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned it from this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxjournal.com/content/tech-tip-really-simple-http-server-python&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very late in learning this :(&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 18:38:16 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/simplehttpserver</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/simplehttpserver</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackathon in PANDA contd</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…
&lt;br /&gt;
I want the event to be a hit among all the participants. It is very difficult to make people get involved at events in a corporate. I was thinking of ways to make them so dropped the next teaser mail stating lot of PANDA goodies are to be awarded as prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not even think what those goodies will be. Later gave some thought on it and learnt swags are main take aways in a Hackathon. So immediately designed a laptop sticker with Hackathon logo. Also designed a paper friend similar to &lt;a href=&quot;foldable.me&quot;&gt;Foldable.me&lt;/a&gt; with application and Hackathon logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the event can’t be organized on a single day we planned for it run over the week.With the final day the teams need to present it to judges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created a sharepoint page with a workflow to automatically intimate the idea overview to the management on teams submission. Initially thought of having filteration on the ideas submitted.But since every team was busy with regular work, each team submitted only one idea with collection of features in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to typical hackathon where prototype needs to be shown we dropped the idea of prototyping since there are lot process involved in any DB level changes also supporting the business should not come to halt.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 19:31:21 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/pandahackathon2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/pandahackathon2</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackathon in PANDA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Being part of Chennai Geeks group and reading the blogs of my tech friends was eagerly waiting be part of the next Hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jealous in me started buiding up when my friends company hosts hackathon for their employees to showcase their geeky skills.As said earlier was closely following up the various forums on next event to get participate to learn and to get some great exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time I was just thinking about why don’t we organize a Hackathon in our company which will be first of its kind.But doing it for the entire company is difficult , hence changed my decision and made it little narrower to the project I am working in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the thought came in I was looking for oppurtunity to make it real. I have just made my experiences in oraganizing this event for my project in this blog post…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
 Once I decided that the event should be organized for the project, I started with preparations for it.But I had the following questions&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;  How the event is going to oragnized focussing on the application?
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; How am I going to convince management to invest time for this event?
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; How will the team members react to the event and what will be the level of participation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just made my mind clear since the event is first of its kind it should be organized to meet all the expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first meeting&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I just prepared a typical formal presentation about the event and met with the management team of my project to convey them the real concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is neccessary to showcase the outcomes of anything to management to convince them. So in the presentation I made it clear that what would be major outcomes of the event. It was the three category that made the management to give &lt;strong&gt;Go Signal&lt;/strong&gt; for me to proceed.The ideas/hacks were categorized as &lt;br /&gt;
*Technical&lt;br /&gt;
*Functional&lt;br /&gt;
*Data&lt;br /&gt;
*Process&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team members need to develop something on any of these categories with respect to the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the them clear next constraint we had was the duration of the event. Since team members had their daily routines and support to business is of top priority the event can’t be organized for whole day. It was also not possible to conduct it during the weekends similar to typical Hackathons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With clear condition of &lt;strong&gt;Not to distrupt business support&lt;/strong&gt; management gave me green signal to proceed with the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately I prepared a teaser mail and gave a heads up to the team members about the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;to be contd..&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 03:43:24 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/pandahackathon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/pandahackathon</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My thoughts does not work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As my post topic my thought does not work. Yeah this word was new to me when I entered my college.Haven’t heard in my english classes it was SSN that thought me this yes it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thoughtworks.com/&quot;&gt;ThoughtWorks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With fun-filled bus journey to my college I learn this word and I dunno why I liked this word very much even now i am crazy about the word..It was my first year my seniors one day said this word and one guy  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/jeygeethan&quot;&gt;Geethan&lt;/a&gt; from my bus is gonna have it in his tag in near future.I was very confused and puzzled…Said to my self wat these guys talking like this “When we giants like CTS, Infosys,Wipro,HCL wat this Thought Works is gonna do with my career? “.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later during just like some other day discussion in bus I talked over to Geethan. That day was really a game changer in which I think about my college life and plans. He was gr8 techy guy. Later he has also guided me till date in few things. He was the same guy who introduced me the word &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topcoder.com/&quot;&gt;Top Coder&lt;/a&gt; which gave really a great things that we should do during our college days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be it’s since I said those words or something written this word is draining my mind till date.Yeah it’s Thought Works the agile company I’m talking about. From the day I said those above said lines it became my main aim in college life.If i gonna land up in a job it should be onli thought works I decided.Preparation started in First Year itself..
Learnt the real art of Programming, Java, Graphics, Agile Technology so many to be frank wat ever I learnt, I learnt in such way that it will help me in my first work @ ThoughtWorks. Whenever my friends speak about jobs I just say this words to them that I will get it for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Days passed after four years of dreams and severe preparation it was time for me to get my offer letter :):) Yup it’s placement time in our college and  the very first company tat visited  of course the company tat had my dream word in english “THought Works” …With lots of hopes and dreams and hard work and confidence attended the campus placement but in vain all my dreams went in a fraction of second with my name not in the selection list from first round itself… My life was ended..Put leave for my college for next three days and cried all days .. I was never like this in my life…With constant updates of student who cleared the rounds, my sadness incresed also my prayers for them increased..but for those for whom I prayed they too din get through..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be my over confidence has caused me failure!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark my words “I’ve not cleared your recruitment process now, but I’ll surely get into in near future!! Be ready to invite me ThoughtWorks….”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All de best TW for ur new includes:(&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 13:31:57 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/mythoughtsdoesnotwork</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.balaaagi.me/posts/mythoughtsdoesnotwork</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>